Guide to Miscellaneous Financial Materials Concerning Non-Metallic Mineral Companies Operating in the North American West
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Miscellaneous financial materials concerning non-metallic mineral companies operating in the North American West
1854-1951
Ndy37
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
(2 boxes)
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning non-metallic mining companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include charters, company descriptions, company correspondence, letters and notices to the stockholders, prospectuses, reports, stock exchange petitions, proxy statements, and reorganization and readjustment notices and agreements. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Most of these financial materials were part of a collection acquired by Yale in 1922 from William H. Brown of West Haven, Conn. The collection, initially called the William H. Brown Statistical Library, numbered some 23,000 documents and covered the years 1890 to 1917. The collection was merged with similar materials already in the University Library and later expanded by gifts from Brown and others to become what is now known as the William H. Brown Collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning non-metallic mining companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include charters, company descriptions, company correspondence, letters and notices to the stockholders, prospectuses, reports, stock exchange petitions, proxy statements, and reorganization and readjustment notices and agreements. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically by company name.
Nonmetallic minerals -- West (U.S.); Mining corporations -- West (U.S.); Proxy statements -- Specimens.; William H. Brown Collection
- Boston-Montana Corporation, 1922-1924; Ndy37 U2 +B656; (16 documents) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Boston Montana Mining Corporation, 1927; Ndy37 U2 +B657; (8 documents) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Consolidated Rock Products Company, 1926-1929; Ndy37 U2 +C76; (3 documents) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Dexteretta Mines Company, 1916?; Ndy37 U2 +D524; (2 documents) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Freeport Sulphur Company, 1939; Ndy37 U2 +F875; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Kasaan Bay Mining Company, 1901; Ndy37 U2 +K15; (2 documents) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Kentucky Mining and Manufacturing Company, 1854; Ndy37 U2 +K395; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- New England and Montana Mining Company, 1902; Ndy37 U2 +N415; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Texas Gulf Sulphur Company, 1909-1951; Ndy37 U2 +T312; (25 documents) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Utah Apex Mining Company, 1917; Ndy37 U2 +Ut1; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- United Mineral Lands Corporation, 1927; Ndy37 U2 +Un3; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Western Onyx and Marble Company, 1896; Ndy37 U2 +W525; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 11)